# Robert S. Harris

183 Sterling Street, Brooklyn, New York 11225 Cell: 646.620.4438

Email:<u>rharris@worldshaker.com</u>
Portfolio: <u>http://www.worldshaker.com</u>
LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/robertsharris

# **UI/UX Designer**

## Summary

User Experience Designer who is an experienced UI Developer, Design Technologist, and Web Producer with over 10 years of experience in the field. Produced and implemented Web solutions from wireframes, visual designs, and working prototypes to production. Skilled in the UX processes and methodologies from discovery to delivery. Extensive experience with CSS3, HTML5, Adobe CC, and JavaScript including ReactJS, jQuery, AngularJS, adaptive, RWD. Technical experience serves as the foundation and tools in my user experience work, and it makes me a well-rounded UX designer. The UX design tools are Figma, Sketch, Miro, Mural and Optimal Workshop. User advocate who is committed to discovering the problem that the business and users are facing and designing and delivering solutions to those problems.

## **Technical Skills**

Figma, Adobe CC (Photoshop, XD, Dreamweaver, Illustrator, Premiere), InVision Studio, Miro, Mural, Optimal Workshop, Sketch, Justinmind, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material UI, MVC, React, Visual Studio Code, JavaScript (ES6), Node.JS, Jasmine, JSON, Oracle 10, 11, MySQL, SQL, some Python, .Net, SharePoint 2007/2013, Liferay, WordPress, Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics, Facebook Business Suite, Shopify.

Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Project, Visio, Windows 10, Mac OS, Sun Solaris.

## Experience

# User Experience Design Immersive Student, 03/2021 - 6/2021 General Assembly, New York, NY

- 12-week, 450+ hour User Experience Design program focused on user-centered design methods, design thinking skills, team collaboration, and client relations.
- Created low-fidelity sketches/wireframes using pens/pencils and Sketch.
- Worked as lead information architect on group projects creating sitemaps and wireframes.
- Used Figma to design mid-fidelity and hi-fidelity wireframes working towards working prototypes with full interaction.
- Conducted user research using interviews, contextual inquiry, affinity mapping, personas, jobs to be done, journey
  mapping, competitive and comparative analysis, and heuristic analysis to gather insights during the discovery
  phase.
- Used Miro to create user flows, wire flows, and site maps.
- Created presentation slides to present findings from research and designs.
- Conducted usability testing.
- Worked on the user experience design for Fade Technology Solutions contributing to the discovery phase, leading the information architecture, and contributing to the visual design of their dashboard and administration solution.

#### Contractor - Web Producer/UI Designer, SharePoint - KPMG (4/2017 - 5/2020)

- Led KPMG's key business units to successfully migrate their US Portal sites from SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2013.
- Designed and produced working prototypes and solutions for the business units on the US Portal.
- Collaborated with the lead UX designer on the facilitation of discovery sessions to identify the problem, and define project scope.
- Worked with lead UX designer to interview stakeholders, site owners, and end-users to gather and synthesize data
  to gain insights on the business and end-user needs.
- Acted as the primary liaison between sponsors, site-owners, stakeholders, and the design and development team communicating business requirements, and feature requests, and bugs.

- Led the designing, building, testing, and delivery of the solutions for the KPMG's Local Office(enterprise-level sites).
- Guided site owners and content managers on mapping their content via a content inventory tool to the UI components/widgets.
- Collaborated with the lead UX designer on the visual designs for various solutions.
- Led the presentations of solutions to stakeholders, sponsors, and site-owners during the project kick-off phase.
- Built SharePoint lists based on requirements gathered from users to map and organize information, important documents, assets, and office contacts.
- Provided guidance to the site owners and stakeholders on adherence to KPMG's brand guidelines, including colors, images, videos, and other assets.
- Established measurable goals of success (S.M.A.R.T) and KPIs for the implementation of the solution with feedback from site owners, and stakeholders.
- Designed, built, and deployed KPMG's Local Office solutions, which greatly improved firmwide communications and collaboration between offices and intra-office communications and collaboration.
- · Conducted user acceptance tests before publishing sites and content live on the US Portal.
- Conducted knowledge transfer sessions with site owners, and content managers training them in building pages, creating and managing lists, and creating rich HTML content.
- Led the effort, alongside the UX team, and stakeholders, to build out a SPA (Single Page Application) for the firm's Code of Conduct microsite using Adobe Photoshop, CSS, HTML, and AngularJS within SharePoint CMS.
- Provided ongoing support for the US Portal business unit's site owners including site updates, solutions, and guidance.

#### Web Producer | UI/UX Developer | Design Technologist - WorldShaker Interactive, Inc. (9/1998 - Present)

- Redesigned <a href="http://www.worldshaker.com">http://www.worldshaker.com</a> using Sketch for sketches and Figma for mid-fidelity and hi-fidelity wireframes and visual design and prototype.
- Developed http://www.worldshaker.com using React, Bootstrap and Visual Studio One, and HTML5, CSS3.
- Converted PSDs into working semantic HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for desktop and mobile devices which improved the user experience of the clients' enterprise-level and consumer websites.
- Developed working prototypes for the A/B testing phase of the redesign of http://www.saks.com in 2007.
- Worked with the information architects on wireframes.
- Performed cross-browser and cross-platform testing and debugging during the QA and UAT project phases.

## PROJECTS (2007-2013):

Sony Music (4/2010-7/2010) KGB (7-2010-9/2010) Dow Jones: wsj.com (4/2008-9/2008) SAKS: saks.com (3/2007 - 5-2007) Cline Davis Mann: (5/2007 - 7/2007)

TV Guide Online: tvguideonline.com (7/2006 - 11/2006) Interactive Media Associates: touchtunes.com (1/2010 - 4/2010) Turner Broadcasting Inc.: thefrisky.com (9/2009 - 11/2009) Greentech Media (1/2009 - 9/2009) Icon Nicholson (10/2008 - 11/2008) KBSP - bmwusa.com (1/2011-2/2011) Burson Marsteller (2/2011 - 3/2011) Regan Campbell Ward (12/2010) CAHG - Omnicom Media Group (7/2013 - 9/2013)

#### Contractor - UI/UX Developer - Pershing - BNY Mellon (4/2014 - 1/2016)

- Configured clients' sites in Liferay CMS and worked on migration from Liferay 6.0 to 6.2.
- Developed the adaptive, ADA, and desktop branding experiences for netxinvestor.com clients, which improved the overall user experience of the brands' sites.
- Performed cross-browser and cross-platform and multi-device development, testing, and QA-ing using Firefox, Chrome, and Chrome Emulator, and IE as debugging tools.
- · Worked with the backend development team and the QA team to identify, debug, and fix defects.
- Led the development team in refactoring the HTML for my assigned brands.
- Worked with the Business Analyst on requirements gathering for the various Web projects.
- URLs include netxinvestor.com, tdwealth.netxinvestor.com, coi.netxinvestor.com, firstrepublicsecurities.netxinvestor.com, orientalonline.netxinvestor.com, santander.netxinvestor.com, santandersecurities.netxinvestor.com, kis.netxinvestor.com, citi.netxinvestor.com and many more.

#### Education

Bernard M. Baruch, New York, NY — Bachelor of Business Administration — Computer Information Systems